

### **ABHISHEK BANERJEE**

#### **PROFILE**

COMPUTER INSTRUCTOR & BACK OFFICE MANAGER WITH OVER 2YEARS OF EXPERIENCE. **CURRENTLY PROVIDING ADMINISTRATIVE & EDUCATIONAL SUPPORT TO OVER 50 STAFF** MEMBERS AND STUDENTS IN GOVT SCHOOL (W.B) AND INTERFACING WITH FACILITY MANAGEMENT IN (I.T) INDUSTRY. I POSSESS STRONG MULTI-TASKING SKILLS, WITH ABILITY SIMULTANEOUSLY MANAGE SEVERAL **PROJECTS** AND SCHEDULES. IN (I.T)MANAGERIAL AND **BIOTECHNOLOGICAL** EQUIPMENT, OPERATIONS AND **SERVICE** PROVIDERS. TECH SAVVY AND EFFICIENCY FOCUSED.

#### CONTACT

abaneriee.india@rediffmail.com

+91 8116531223, +91 9333143898

MANASHI APARTMENT F-1A, KN ROAD BERHAMPORE, MURSHIDABAD, INDIA WEST BENGAL, 742101.

#### **ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS**

• Hiking • Travel

**KEY SKILLS**-STRONG INTERPERSONAL &COMMUNICATION SKILLS.ABILITY TO WORK **COLLABORATIVELY AS A PART OF A TEAM.PROBLEM SOLVING.METICULOUS** ATTENTION TO DETAIL.EXCELLENT **ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS.** 

PERSONAL DETAILS-DATE OF BIRTH-16NOV 1991.

**NATIONALITY-INDIAN.** 

LANGUAGE KNOWN-**ENGLISH, HINDI, BENGALI** 

# **RFSUMF**

## **EXPERIENCE**

COMPUTER INSTRUCTOR, EXTRAMARKS EDUCATION INDIA, PVT, LTD, D-180, SECTOR 63, NOIDA, U.P -201301.MARCH2021-PRESENT. TO IMPART COMPUTER EDUCATION TO STUDENT IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE CURRICULUM PESCRIBED BY THE (WBBSE) & (WBCHSE) GOVT OF WEST BENGAL. ASSISTING &PROVIDING ADMINISTRATIVE SUPPORT TO THE SCHOOL STUFF IN COMPUTER RELATED MATTER.ENSURING SMOOTH RUNNING OF THE ENTIRE PROJECT AT THE

ALLOCATED SCHOOL IN COORDINATION WITH SCHOOL STAFF, DISTRICT COORDINATOR AND OTHER COMPETENT AUTHORITIES.MAINTAINING ,PLANNING &EXECUTING OF THE WORK STATION & COMPUTER LABORATORY OF THE SCHOOL.

BACK OFFICE MANAGER, S.P NANIBAME, PAIKPARA, PO-SURI, DIST-BIRBHUM, 731101, WESTBENGAL, INDIA.AUGUST 2018- DECEMBER 2019. - BACK OFFICE MANAGER WITH 1YEAR4MONTHS OF EXPERIENCE IN A PETROCHEMICAL COMPANY, ASSISTING MORE THAN 20 MEMBERS OF TEAM OF ADMINISTRATIVE AS WELL AS FIELD OPERATION OF NATIONAL LEVEL CONCERN.

- 1. WORK EXPERIENCE (PROJECT)-IOCL MATHURA REFINARY MECHANICAL TANK CLEANING AND HYDROCARBON RECOVERY.
- 2. CAIRN INDIA LIMITED BARMER WELLPAD SLUDGE PROCESSING HYDROCARBON RECOVERY & WASTE MINIMIZATION.PURIFICATION &CLARIFICATION OF HFO/LDO CRUDE OIL & WATER PURIFICATION.

#### **EDUCATION**

- 1. MATRICULATION (10TH) WITH (45.8%)- CENTRAL BOARD OF SECONDARY EDUCATION(CBSE), KENDRIYA VIDYALAYA BERHAMPORE, 2008.
- 2. HIGH SECONDARY EXAMINATION (12TH) WITH (54%)-WESTBENGAL COUNCIL OF HIGH SECONDARY EXAMINATION (WBCHSE), GITARAM ACADEMY2011.
- 3. BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN (MOLECULAR BIOLOGY, ZOOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE). WITH (53%) UNIVERSITY OF KALYANI, JIAGANJ SRIPAT SINGH COLLEGE.WESTBENGAL, INDIA, AUGUST-2015 4. MASTERS OF SCIENCE IN BIOTECHNOLOGY.WITH (CGPA-6.98/64.06%).WITH A RESEARCH PROJECT IN COMPARATIVE GENOMICS. JIS UNIVERSITY, KOLKATA, WEST BENGAL, INDIA, JUNE-
- 5. CERTIFICATION IN 1. COMPUTER FUNDAMENTALS. 2. COMPUTER HARDWARE & NETWORKING. (WITH69%) BRAINWARE COMPUTER ACADEMY.WEST BENGAL, INDIA, AUGUST2010 - OCTOBER 2011.
- 6. SENIOR DIPLOMA IN ARTS PART -2.WITH (64%, 1ST DIVISION) -SARBABHARATIYA SANGEET O SANSKRITI PARISHAD.2006-2007.

PROJECT ACCOMPLISHED- 1. Human Diseased & Non Diseased Genes: An Insight from Comparative Genomics. (Presented at ACMBHD-2018, NATIONAL SEMINOR, APPLICATION OF CELLULAR AND MOLECULAR BIOLOGY IN HUMAN AND DISEASES, KOLKATA, W.B) Ranked 3<sup>rd</sup> position.2. Characterization of Municipal solid waste: A case study at Agarpara Dumpsite in Kolkata. (Presented at 106TH ISCA 2019 JALANDHAR, PUNJAB.INDIAN SCIENCE CONGRESS ASSOCIATION).

TECHNICAL SKILLS- 1. COMPUTER /IT - MS OFFICE, INTERNET HANDLING, WINDOWS, LINUX, SERVER2003, BASIC ELECTRONIC

- 2. BIOTECHNOLOGICAL SKILLS- MICROSCOPY, SPECTROSCOPY, ELISA, DATA ANALYSIS, ELECTROPHORESIS, HPLC, PCR, GENOMICS, CENTRIFUGATION, MAKING BUFFER SOLUTION.
- 3. MANAGERIAL SKILLS- Assisting and supporting management. Assisting the Front Office team. Organizing staff meetings and updating calendars. Processing company receipts, invoices, and bills. Performing basic admin duties including printing, sending emails, and ordering office supplies. Performing market research.